## OFGEHA GELANA

#### AI RESEARCHER AND BACKEND DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

+251935070773

✓ ofgehagelana2019@gmail.com

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

www.github.com

www.website.com

www.linkedin.com

## **EDUCATION**

## 2019 - 2023 ASTU UNIVERSITY

- Computer Science and Engineering
- Bachelor of Science
- GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

## **SKILLS**

- Python
- Django Framework
- Machine Learning
- RESTful API Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Version Control (Git)
- Teamwork
- Effective Communication

## LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Amharic(Fluent)
- Oromo(Fluent)

## **PROFILE**

Eager Python Django developer with four years exploiting model-template-view architectural pattern of Django framework to shorten development times and reduce design costs. Specializes in creating accessible, data-driven web assets with AI integration. Keen to apply expansive development knowledge to deliver fast, efficient Healthcare management system projects.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Ethiopian Artificial Intelligence Institution 2023 - PRESENT

AI Researcher and developer

- Designs and implements AI software solutions, integrating ML models into scalable apps for efficiency.
- Develops AI products, using ML frameworks like TensorFlow, PyTorch, ensuring robustness.
- Engineers AI infrastructure, deploying ML models in production, ensuring reliability and scalability.

# Information Network Security Agency 2022 - 2023 Python Django Developer (Intern II)

- Leads projects, architects scalable solutions, and implements best practices for performance and security.
- Designs robust backend systems with Django, RESTful APIs, and database optimizations for efficient data handling.
- Contributes to complex Django apps, collaborates crossfunctionally, delivering high-quality using Agile.

2021 - 2022

#### EthioTelecom

Cybersecurity Engineer (Intern I)

- Implements and manages security solutions to protect networks and systems from cyber threats.
- Manages security operations, monitors for security incidents, and responds to incidents as needed.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Coursera
Coursera
Coursera
Coursera
Udemy